President's Office Records, 1927-1981
University of Houston Libraries
- Investment Investigation (Box 56-59)
  - Vice President Singleton's In-house Investigation (Box 56-59)
    - Douglas G. MacLean, Vice President (Box 57, Folder 10-20)
      When Charles F. McElhinney retired in 1973, Douglas G. MacLean replaced him as the University's top financial officer. During MacLean's tenure, Sam Harwell, J. Treadway Brogdon, and Harold W. Scott all answered to him. After the improper activity was uncovered, MacLean was placed on a six-month administrative leave with pay. When the UH regents announced their findings regarding the investigation, one of their recommendations was that MacLean not be kept on staff when his leave of absence expired. The others who had been responsible for supervising Harwell's investment program either resigned or retired. This sub-sub-series relates directly to Douglas MacLean and the folders are arranged chronologically.
      - Management Services, 1971-1973 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Financial and Management Services, 1972-1974 (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - Congressional Hearing Materials, 1973 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Scheduled absences from office of, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - Wheaton College President Search Committee 1974 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - Management Service, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - Financial and Mgmt. Services, 1973-1975 (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Management Services, 1974-1978 (Box 57, Folder 17)
      - Management Services, 1975-1976 (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - Financial and Management Services, 1976-1978 (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Mailroom, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence (Box 57, Folder 21-34)
      This sub-sub-series consists primarily of correspondence with various entities including, but not limited to, financial institutions, banks, law firms, and various university departments. Folders are arranged chronologically.
      - Memo-Faculty Women's Salaries, July 19, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 21)
      - Mineral Reserve, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 22)
      - Graduate Extension Courses-Memo, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 23)
      - University Officials, Minimum Reserve Requirements (Banking Institutions), Proposed Air Travel Procedures, Minor Capital Improvement Program, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 25)
      - Task Force 8 Report-Memo, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence and Financial Transactions with Financial Institutions, 1974-1976 (Box 57, Folder 27)
      - With Financial Institutions, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 28)
      - Interoffice Memos Relating to Short-term Investment Issues, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 29)
      - New Accounts-Memo, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 30)
      - Memo: Oppenheimer, Rosenberg, Kelleher, Wheatley, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 31)
      - Mini Computer Lease: Miller to Singleton Memo, 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 32)
      - Short-term Investment, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 33)
      - Backup for Computer Related Memos, undated (Box 57, Folder 34)
    - Financial, Banking, and Legal Materials (Box 57-59)
      This sub-sub-series consists of extensive financial records and reports relating to the university's short-term investments. Of special interest are Brogdam's Report on Short-term Investments and Hoffman's testimony before the House of Representatives Committee on Cash Management. Folders are arranged chronologically.
      - Financial Report: Fiscal Year Ended August 31, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 35)
      - Covington Knox Incorporated Statement, February 8-July 8, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 36)
      - White Weld and Company Confirmations for trades, March 15-July 5, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 37)
      - Lehman Government Securities Inc., March 15-July 8, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 38)
      - Covington Knox billing statements Trades executed, Feb. 8-July 20, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 39)
      - Covington Knox Incorporated Statement, Feb. 8-July 20, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Confidential: Comments on Temporary Investment Matters, December 1, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Certificates of Deposit, December 6, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Originals Subpoenaed District. Attorney State Securities Board v. C. Knox, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 4-5)
      - Miscellaneous Documents Received from University of Houston Re: CKI, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - University of Houston Analysis and Project on Building Use Fees, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - Budget Activity Report, 1977-1978 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Financial Report: For the Three Months Ended November 30, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 9)
      - Press Release-U.H. System Vice President for Fiscal Affairs Named, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - R.D. Luckey-Assistant State Auditor, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Woodlands Campus, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - Bank Balances, Dec. 1977-Jan. 1978 (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - Summary of Known P and I Payments Due, January 12, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 14)
      - Schedule of Short-Terms Investment Credits, August 31, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 15)
      - Daily Claims Summary, Jan. 10-March 28, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 16)
      - Interrogatories Submitted by Japan California Bank (Short-term Investment), July 20, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 17)
      - Cash Position, Jan. 6-Oct. 2, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 18)
      - Bates College of Law, Flood Prevention Central Campus, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 19)
      - Chemical Bank, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 20)
      - Ehrlich-Bober and Company-Defendants Original Answer, Defendants Counterclaim, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 21)
      - Ehrlich-Bober and Company, Inc., vs. the University of Houston, Dismissal of Action, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 22)
      - Estimated Construction Funds Through August 31, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 23)
      - List of Salaries (Handwritten), 1978 (Box 58, Folder 24)
      - Physical Plant Projects (Prioritization), 1978 (Box 58, Folder 25)
      - University of Houston-Clear Lake, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 26)
      - "University of Houston Covington Knox Project March 1978", 1978 (Box 58, Folder 27-28)
      - Final Inspection Report, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 29)
      - Brogdams Report on Short-term Investments, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 30)
      - Testimony Before House of Representatives Committee on Cash Management Dr. Phillip G. Hoffman, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 31)
      - Testimony Before House of Representative Committee on Cash Management, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 32)
      - Continuing Education Center Fee Shortages, undated (Box 58, Folder 33)
      - University of Houston System: Accounting/Financial Operational Review, undated (Box 58, Folder 34)
      - Report on the Use of Private Consultants, undated (Box 58, Folder 35)
      - Short Term Investment Control, undated (Box 58, Folder 36)
      - Analysis of Microcomputer Lease, undated (Box 58, Folder 37)
      - Mr. Benjamin N. Woodson N-8, undated (Box 58, Folder 38)
      - Summary of Amounts Approved and Claimed and Audit Adjustments, undated (Box 58, Folder 39)
      - Analysis of Mission Self-Study Task Force and Final Report, undated (Box 58, Folder 40)
      - Analysis of Mission Self-Study Task Force 8: Final Report, undated (Box 58, Folder 41)
      - Photocopies of Checks Short-term Investment plus others, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - General Research and Reference materials (Box 59, Folder 2-23)
      This sub-sub series consist of several different types of materials including photocopies of ledger entries and checks, correspondence, and remarks by President Hoffman before the Higher Education Committee.
      - Short-term Investment, 1976-1978 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Short-term Investment, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Short-term Investment, Including Board of Regents Investment Committee Minutes and Financial Ledgers, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Short-term Investment, January to June 1978 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Short-term Investment, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Short-term Investment Reports, 1974-1978 (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - Short-term Investment Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Short-term Investment, President's Report, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Short-term Investment Items, 1974-1977 (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - A Guide to the University Planning Process, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Coordinating Board Salary Rate Study, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - American Council on Education "Institute for Academic Deans", 1974 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - State Ad Volorem Tax, June 1, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - The University of Texas System Investment Practices and Policies, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Self-Study Extracts, undated (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - Dr. Philip G. Hoffman Revised Documents, undated (Box 59, Folder 17)
      - U.H. System Information and Requested Documentation from Other System/Campus Universities, undated (Box 59, Folder 18)
      - Short-term Loan Funding, undated (Box 59, Folder 19)
      - Texas Education Code, undated (Box 59, Folder 20)
      - Blank: "Reply Affidavit", undated (Box 59, Folder 21)
      - Datapoint File N-9, undated (Box 59, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous Materials Relating to Short-term Investments, undated (Box 59, Folder 23)
- Oversize (Box 62-63)
  - Oversized Financial Records, undated (Box 62)
  - Newspaper Articles, Investment Materials, 1976-1978 (Box 63)
- Council of Presidents (Box 59-60)
  This series contains ten folders that date from 1965-1978. The Council of Presidents was a group of Presidents from the Public Senior Colleges and Universities in the State of Texas. This group examined various issues related to higher education including continuing education, pay raises for state employees, medical and health fees, and many other issues.
  - Council of Presidents, 1965 (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - Council of Presidents, 1966-1972 (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - Council of Presidents, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 26-27)
  - Council of Presidents, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 28)
  - Council of Presidents, 1975 (Box 59, Folder 29)
  - Council of Presidents, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 30)
  - Council of Presidents, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 31)
  - Council of Presidents, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Council of Presidents, 1978 (Box 60, Folder 2)
- Speeches/Oral Interview/Biographical Sketch (Box 60, Folder 3-5)
  - Speeches: Philip G. Hoffman (16 speeches), 1962-1977 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Oral Interview w/tapes, May 8, 1985 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Sketch, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 5)
- Business Travel (Box 60, Folder 6-20)
  This series dates from 1962 to 1976 and contains materials relating to trips Hoffman took and the automobile he used while in his position at UH.
  - Jacksonville Speech and Degree, 1962 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Brazil-PGH Engineering/OAS/AID, 1962 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Trip-European, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Trip-Algerian, June 17-July 5, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Trip-Germany, April, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Trip-Hawaiian Carnival Summer Alumni Federation, Summer 1966 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Trips-U.S.S.R., March, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 12-13)
  - Trip-European/South Africa, March 30-April 14, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Trip-Guadalajara, December 5-10, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 15-16)
  - Trip-Korea-Japan, December 3-19, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Trip-Brazil, June, 17-26, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Trip-Taiwan, November 7-17, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - Automobile, 1961-1971 (Box 60, Folder 20)
- President's Christmas Cards (Box 61, Folder 1-15)
  This series consists of fifteen folders dating from 1961 to 1977. It contains samples of the Christmas Cards sent out by the President's Office during Philip Hoffman's term as president.
  - Correspondence President's Christmas Card List, 1961 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1965 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1972 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - President's Christmas Cards, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 15)